This is the solutions video for the command line arguments section.
本视频将讲解命令行参数部分的解决方案
We first have to define get_input_args function.
首先定义函数 get_input_args
The doc string indicates,
这里的文档字符串指出
there are no arguments passed into the function,
该函数没有输入参数
but we return parse_args.
但会返回解析器参数 parse_args
The data structure that stores the command line arguments.
也即存储着命令行参数的数据结构
First thing we have to do,
首先
is create the parser object.
创建解析器对象
Here, name parser.
将其命名为 parser
Next, we have to create the three command line arguments.
接着 进行三个命令行参数的创建
The first 'dir,' is the command line argument that defaults to the pet_images folder,
第一个命令行参数是 “dir” 默认为 pet_images 文件夹
and is just the path to the images.
其实就是图像路径
Next, is the command line argument 'arch,' which we've
第二个命令行参数是 “arch”
defaulted to 'vgg,' but you could have picked any of the models.
默认为 “vgg” 但你可以改成其它模型
And this is just the chosen model.
这个参数就是用来选择模型的
Finally, we have the dog file.
最后是 “dogfile”
This defaults to 'dognames.txt.'
默认为 “dognames.txt”
It's the text file that contains the dog names.
即包含着犬名的文本文件
Finally, we just return the parser argument.
最后 返回 parser_args
Next, we need to go to the main function where we call get_input_args.
接着 来到调用了函数 get_input_args 的主函数部分
In the main function, we see get_input_args being called with no,
我们可以看到主函数调用了 get_input_args
arguments being passed in, which is correct.
其中没有任何参数 这是对的
And it's returning these command line arguments as the variable in_arg.
函数会将命令行参数返回为变量 in_arg
Next, we also wrote a print statement which is
接着 编写输出语句
temporary and will be removed after we check this code.
这些语句是临时的 等代码检查完毕后 我们就要删除掉这些语句
This print statement just prints out those three command line arguments.
语句的唯一作用就是输出这三个命令行参数
Notice the way they are called is the variable name dot,
注意这些参数的调用方式为
and then the command line argument name.
变量名.命令行参数名
For example, we have in_arg.dir
比如 in_arg.dir
to call that pet_images directory path.
会调用目录路径 pet_images
Now, we're going to run the program to check our code.
接着 运行程序 检查代码
In the terminal window here,
在终端窗口里
I type python check images -h,
输入 python check_images 后面再输入 -h
to get the help file for our program.
从而获取程序的帮助文件
This shows me what the command line arguments are,
从这里可以看出命令行参数有哪些
and what they're expecting for each of them.
了解每个参数的作用
In the second terminal window,
在第二个终端窗口中
I just type python check images.py. Hit enter.
输入 python check_images.py 按下 enter 键
This printed out the default values for my command line arguments.
程序会输出命令行参数的默认值
Pet_images, the default directory,
即默认目录 pet_images
'vgg,' default model architecture,
默认模型结构 vgg
and dogsnames.txt, the default dog file.
默认犬名文本 dogsnames.txt
In this third terminal window,
在第三个终端窗口中
I input the three command line arguments for my 'dir' I just put pets,
我输入了三个命令行参数 dir 对应 pets
and that's what I see being print.
可以看到这里有相应的输出
For my architecture, I put 'resnet,' and that's what I see printed here.
结构 arch 对应 resnet 这里也有相应的输出
And then, for the dog file,
dogfile
I put dnames.txt, and that's what I see being printed here.
对应 dnames.txt 这里也有相应的输出
So, it seems that all my code is working properly.
由此可见 代码无误